<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>perfectly spherical</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/</link><description>Recent content on perfectly spherical</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://perfectly-spherical.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Minecraft Modpack Dev Is Hell</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/mc-dev-is-hell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/mc-dev-is-hell/</guid><description>So about that modpack thing DevOps for Minecraft is absolute hell. Let me regale you with some tales of the shit I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through in the past day:
Mob spawn rates are dramatically different on multiplayer servers. I have a mod in this pack called Scape &amp;amp; Run: Parasites. It adds freaky biological horrors, a la the Flood. It&amp;rsquo;s actually quite well designed and I like the concepts behind it, with the parasites getting stronger as they consume more biomass.</description></item><item><title>Minecraft: The Perfectly Spherical LP</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/minecraft-lp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/minecraft-lp/</guid><description>Have you ever wanted to watch me, my new boss, and a bunch of other nerds play Minecraft? No? Too bad. Announcing The Perfectly Spherical LP, a project in which I attempt to shepherd the people I now live with through my own insane modpack.
Be amazed by our incompetence! Be shocked by the terrible monsters! Watch in awe as I demonstrate exactly why I&amp;rsquo;m not a popular indie dev yet!</description></item><item><title>About That Moving Thing</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/news-sep-21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/news-sep-21/</guid><description>The move is pretty much done! And there&amp;rsquo;s a specific thing I mean by &amp;ldquo;pretty much&amp;rdquo;. I have most of my shit together at this point, but there&amp;rsquo;s more Ikea trips planned to acquire things like a non-cardtable desk and the obligatory shark plushie. I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten settled in, mostly unpacked, and everything&amp;rsquo;s already going according to&amp;ndash;well, not the plan, so much as the kind of rapid-fire decisions that happen when you get four nerds under one roof and they start pitching ideas at each other.</description></item><item><title>Bullets Per Minute and Control</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/bpm-and-control/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/bpm-and-control/</guid><description>Bullets Per Minute is a fun game. In the vein of Crypt of the NecroDancer, it&amp;rsquo;s a mixture of a rhythm game and another genre&amp;ndash;in this case, it&amp;rsquo;s a rhythm FPS. Your actions must occur on the beat&amp;ndash;shooting, reloading, dashing, jumping, everything (except maybe your ultimate ability, if you find one). It feels fun as hell. The soundtrack is, fittingly, metal as fuck. The gun designs are visually appealing&amp;ndash;but more than that, each gun has its own unique feel, because of how their firing and reloading styles differ.</description></item><item><title>Hellwave Roadkill Devlog 6</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/hwrk-devlog-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/hwrk-devlog-6/</guid><description>All Quiet On The Monstrous Front. I haven&amp;rsquo;t got anything pretty or graphical to show you this week, because A) I had a lot of cleaning to do this week and B) what I did get done was nonvisual. See, part of good programming practices is laying out the groundwork to make the fun parts work well. I could just slap together something that works right now, and&amp;ndash;well, it&amp;rsquo;d work right now&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;d be hard to build off of, like a shack that was built without a foundation and thus struggles to hold much weight.</description></item><item><title>Visual Effects</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/visual-effects/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/visual-effects/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s make this simple. Visual effects&amp;ndash;AKA the &amp;ldquo;look&amp;rdquo; part of &amp;ldquo;look and feel&amp;rdquo;, the stuff that flies around the screen to tell you that Things are Happening&amp;ndash;should be at least sort of obvious. Enemies leak blood when they&amp;rsquo;re shot, rock walls make sparks when your pickaxe hits them, bombs have a big cloud of fire and smoke when they go off, your mage&amp;rsquo;s spell creates a lightshow when it&amp;rsquo;s finished casting.</description></item><item><title>Discoverability (Your Honor, LoL part 2)</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/league-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/league-part-2/</guid><description>Nobody is building Akshan right. Akshan, as a character, has a very complex set of abilities. One could easily argue that he has the most overloaded kit in the game, right now. He has on-hit effects that can be triggered rapidly with clever skill usage, he has stealth for getting in and movement speed boosts to get out again, he has a movement ability that lets him do all sorts of weird jukes while hosing down enemies with bullets (and which refreshes its cooldown on kill or assist), and he has an ultimate that automatically homes in on its target and does increased damage against enemies with low health.</description></item><item><title>Hellwave Roadkill Devlog 5</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/hwrk-devlog-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/hwrk-devlog-5/</guid><description>Back In The Saddle. The past week or two has been spent mostly working on getting ready for the move, but I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten back into working on HWRK. This time around, I prototyped the Sharpgun:
Finally getting some more work done for Hellwave Roadkill. Placeholder graphics for now, but this is the functionality for the Syringe Shotgun, AKA the Sharpgun.
Plug someone with a syringe, and they&amp;#39;ll slowly bleed serum for you, and won&amp;#39;t move as fast.</description></item><item><title>I Can Swing My Sword, My Diamond Sword (MLHRWM, Part 2)</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/minecraft-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/minecraft-part-2/</guid><description>Diamond is powerful. Everyone knows this. The diamond sword and pick are as iconic as Steve and the Creeper. Efforts to cosplay as Steve inevitably involve some diamond armor. The game is practically built around diamond as the god-tier equipment.
Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about why this sucks. (This is a continuation of part 1.)
It Made Sense At The Time because, when Minecraft was first developed, three important things were true:</description></item><item><title>Big News</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/big-news/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/big-news/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m Moving! Those of you who follow my twitter account might&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that I quit my job recently. Let me explain some more things about that.
First: I got a job. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how many details I wanna give out at the moment, but the plan is I&amp;rsquo;m gonna go work for a startup/incubator type place. It&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting, partly because I won&amp;rsquo;t have the job security of working for a company that&amp;rsquo;s already making big money, but also partly because they&amp;rsquo;re doing some crazy shit.</description></item><item><title>Hellwave Roadkill Devlog 4</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/hwrk-devlog-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/hwrk-devlog-4/</guid><description>Schmovement. It is absolutely essential to me that the movement mechanics feel good to use. More than that&amp;ndash;given the time-attack-esque mechanics of serum and serum consumption, it&amp;rsquo;s important that the player not be limited by movement. It would absolutely suck if the player got lost in a level, and was unable to make it back to a nearby group of enemies before their Serum runs out, due to not having a quick way to get around.</description></item><item><title>Hellwave Roadkill Devlog 3</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/hwrk-devlog-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/hwrk-devlog-3/</guid><description>Sounds Of Death This week, I got a couple important things done, but the one you&amp;rsquo;ll probably wanna hear most is the firing sound I added to the gun!
The gun makes sound now. #HellwaveRoadkill pic.twitter.com/IpWx8MQ51n
&amp;mdash; DanBreez (@dan_breez) July 8, 2021 As mentioned in the tweet, this was synthesized from three CC0 sounds. I wanted to do something similar to what Quake 1&amp;rsquo;s sounds were built out of, and I think this came together nicely.</description></item><item><title>Your Honor, League of Legends (part 1)</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/league-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/league-part-1/</guid><description>Okay but why though Look, League of Legends is huge. It&amp;rsquo;s the game that popularized the model of spending millions of dollars to run an international tournament so that a bunch of impressionable young nerds will spend hundreds on commemorative hero skins and dream of Hitting It Big. League has, rather infamously, 200 years of collective game design experience behind it. It is a household name, either because you play it or because you avoid it like the plague.</description></item><item><title>Credits</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/page/credits/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/page/credits/</guid><description>Patrons This list is updated on the 2nd of each month, after payments are received.
$15 Tier $10 Tier Tupolev
$3 Tier Ebreium, one of the herd, FanOfMostEverything</description></item><item><title>Hellwave Roadkill Devlog 2</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/hwrk-devlog-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/hwrk-devlog-2/</guid><description>Progress: Slow and Steady Right now I&amp;rsquo;m working part-time at Amazon&amp;ndash;yes, that Amazon. Luckily, I work in an airport warehouse, and it&amp;rsquo;s slightly less hellish here than it is in the dreaded Fulfillment Centers, which are exactly as dreary and dystopian as you&amp;rsquo;d expect. Unluckily, it&amp;rsquo;s still modern capitalism, which means it&amp;rsquo;s still fucked.
The good news is, I&amp;rsquo;m making steady progress, despite the time I&amp;rsquo;m having to spend away from development.</description></item><item><title>Feedback</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/feedback/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/feedback/</guid><description>There are two ways to deal with feedback, and they are both wrong. Broadly speaking, you probably fall into one of two groups.
The first group is people who believe that the Customer Is Always Right. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s because you haven&amp;rsquo;t run into a particularly bad customer yet; sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s because you&amp;rsquo;ve seen all too many games fail because they did something utterly mind-bogglingly stupid; but you firmly believe that players will never lead you astray, because who better to tell you if something is fun than the people playing the game?</description></item><item><title>Hellwave Roadkill Dev Log 1</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/hwrk-devlog-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/hwrk-devlog-1/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on a game, in case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know. This might not be as surprising as you&amp;rsquo;d think, depending on how well you know me. I&amp;rsquo;m basically always working on something. That said, a little while ago THIS happened:
Combination https://t.co/21MhdYvSkx
&amp;mdash; El Oshcuro (@DaveOshry) June 20, 2021 In case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, that&amp;rsquo;s the guy who runs New Blood Interactive, which is one of the few publishers I genuinely would love to work with.</description></item><item><title>My Love-Hate Relationship With Minecraft, Part 1</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/minecraft-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/minecraft-part-1/</guid><description>Minecraft is kind of a big deal. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the most popular and most profitable games of the 2010s. It lost the status of Most Popular Ever to Fortnite, but it&amp;rsquo;s still going strong, with a rabidly loyal fanbase and new content constantly on the way. Its simple premise of a world that can be built and broken on a whim drove it to the height of pop-culture awareness early on, and pretty soon it started getting things like monsters, survival mechanics, dungeons, villages, more monsters, more ways to fight those monsters, new dungeons, new treasures, new bossfights&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>I'M RELOADING</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/im-reloading/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/im-reloading/</guid><description>Why, exactly, should this gun reload? I want to start by saying that, even though I fucking love boomershooters, this isn&amp;rsquo;t coming from a &amp;ldquo;Doom didn&amp;rsquo;t have reloading so neither will I!&amp;rdquo; point of view. This is not about cargo cultism. This is not about elitism. This isn&amp;rsquo;t about whether or not games have gotten worse over the past 20 years (maybe) or why they&amp;rsquo;ve gotten worse (it&amp;rsquo;s not any one thing).</description></item><item><title>Small Games</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/small-games/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/small-games/</guid><description>STOP MAKING SUCH HUGE GAMES. HOLY SHIT. A little while ago, Ratchet and Clank: Rift Apart launched. The folks announcing it were proud to say that they got it done without crunch. They rolled the game out the door (to the tune of 70 dollars) without a single case of pushing their workers too hard to make up for a bad schedule.
And then people started complaining that tiny details were missing.</description></item><item><title>What Does Delta TTK Mean?</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/delta-ttk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/delta-ttk/</guid><description>Time To Kill is a measurement of how long it takes for a player to defeat another player in a PVP game. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly used in the first person shooter sphere, especially in games with many players running around the same map. Games with high TTK, like Halo, can feel forgiving&amp;ndash;or they can feel like they&amp;rsquo;re being played in slow-motion. Games with low TTK, like Counter-Strike, can be exciting and fast-paced&amp;ndash;or they can feel exceptionally difficult, like playing chess against a grandmaster.</description></item><item><title>Different Kinds of Fun</title><link>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/different-kinds-of-fun/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 02:40:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://perfectly-spherical.com/posts/different-kinds-of-fun/</guid><description>Fun. It exists. Supposedly. People argue quite a lot about what it is. What counts as fun? What makes one game more fun than the other? Is any game &amp;lsquo;fun&amp;rsquo;, or is that just a thing people say when they can&amp;rsquo;t come up with a reason the game is good?
I propose that the question we&amp;rsquo;re asking is inherently wrong. Fun is not a scalar value. It&amp;rsquo;s not a binary, fun or not-fun.</description></item></channel></rss>